<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.10.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/Scientific-Thinking/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/Scientific-Thinking/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-09-10T09:35:47-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Scientific-Thinking/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Scientific Thinking</title><subtitle>A place to publish my professional work. Topics include operator&apos;s guides, testing how-to&apos;s, and other technical writing.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Cypress Operator’s Guide</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Scientific-Thinking/jekyll/update/2024/09/09/cypress-operator's-guide.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cypress Operator’s Guide" /><published>2024-09-09T11:18:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-09-09T11:18:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Scientific-Thinking/jekyll/update/2024/09/09/cypress-operator&apos;s-guide</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Scientific-Thinking/jekyll/update/2024/09/09/cypress-operator&apos;s-guide.html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="cypress-101">Cypress 101</h2>
<p>Cypress is a friendly, frontend testing tool that resembles legacy testing tools like Selenium. It can test anything that runs in a browser. Published tests may be small and omit any dependencies.</p>

<h3 id="what-does-cypress-offer">What does Cypress Offer?</h3>
<p>Cypress comes complete with a built-in test runner, a Cloud environment, video recordings and test replays to closely examine reported failures.</p>

<h3 id="test-replays">Test Replays</h3>
<p>With Test Replay, Cypress Cloud regenerates the entire UI for viewing the run and debugging CI failures. You can:</p>
<ul>
  <li>watch the simulated version of the app in realtime</li>
  <li>time travel, within the frontend simulator, second by second</li>
  <li>pause at the point-in-time where your test failed</li>
</ul>

<p>If your test results are recorded to Cypress Cloud you do not have to worry about manually reproducing bugs. You can replay the failure directly in the Cloud.</p>

<h3 id="cypress-and-xpaths">Cypress and Xpaths</h3>
<p>Xpaths are usually long, “stringified” locators used to traverse the DOM tree that composes your website. The problem is that they are highly sensitive to change, meaning that the removal of one node in the DOM tree will likely result in an invalid xpath. This will immediately fail your tests.</p>

<p><strong>Cypress does not natively support xpaths.</strong> The <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">cypress-xpath</code> npm package is no longer maintained by the author and is not Cypress-supported.
Refrain from using xpaths when possible.
Instead use chains composed of Cypress methods to achieve the desired result. Read more about Cypress chains in my Cheatsheet.</p>

<h3 id="cypress-and-dependencies">Cypress and Dependencies</h3>
<p>Cypress tests are most effective when written with little to no dependencies between. By default, Cypress resets state between tests, unless otherwise specified in the Cypress config file. Dependencies between tests create distance between tests and assertions. The closer the assertion lives to its test, the faster the resolution.</p>

<p>💡 <strong>Protip</strong> state is reset between Cypress tests by default (I.e. between it blocks). To offset, set <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">testIsolation: false</code> in your Cypress config file.</p>

<h3 id="cypress-chains">Cypress Chains</h3>
<p>Cypress chains are commands strung together to execute sequentially. Chains are a more readable and reliable alternative to using xpath.</p>

<h3 id="cypress-and-iframes">Cypress and iFrames</h3>
<p>There is no easy application of working with <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">iframes</code> in Cypress. Most of the cy DOM traversal commands hard stop the moment they hit <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">#document</code> node inside the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">iframe</code>. Working with <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">iframes</code> will require some custom code.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cypress 101 Cypress is a friendly, frontend testing tool that resembles legacy testing tools like Selenium. It can test anything that runs in a browser. Published tests may be small and omit any dependencies.]]></summary></entry></feed>